（圭一(けいいち)）やらなかったのか？
I didn't do it?
（圭一）夢だってのかよ…
Could it have been a dream?
Then that means
he's still with Satoko.
だったらあいつまだ
沙都子(さとこ)と一緒にいるってことかよ…
F-Fine.
（圭一）い…いいさ
生きてるなら生きてるで
If he's alive, he's alive, so I'll do
it however many times it takes.
何度でもやってやる
Could it be that you're Satoshi?
お前ひょっとして悟史(さとし)なのか？
Oh, well.
もういいさ
そんなことどうでも…
That doesn't mean anything...
- "Curse Killing" Chapter -
Episode 05: APOLOGY
When They Cry
Behind where I looked back
(who's there in the front)?
I raised my nails in the dark
(and slashed the night).
Raindrops become droplets of
blood and drip down the throat.
If you don't have
a place to go back to...
...then stop here on my finger.
I'll take you away
along with that finger.
To the unopenable
forest where cicadas cry.
You can't turn back anymore.
（圭一）やっぱりバイクはない
As I thought, no bike.
鍵…かけてないのか？
It's not locked?
（気象予報士）
それでは今日のお天気です
And now the weather.
Today, due to shifting high
pressure unlike yesterday...
今日は
この移動性高気圧のおかげで―
昨日の天気とは打って変わって
全国的に穏やかに晴れる見込みです
...it seems nice and
warm across the country.
え～そしてこの高気圧
（圭一）うん？
Yes, and since this high
pressure is from the continent...
大陸育ちの高気圧なので
とても乾いた空気を…
...it contains very dry air.
- Yesterday's dinner?
（圭一）昨日の夕食？
For two people.
それも ２人分
やっぱり生きてるのか
So he's really alive?
Where did Satoko go?
沙都子はどこに行ったんだ？
What's this noise?
The bath?
風呂か！
なんでこんな朝早くから…
Why so early in the morning?
うん？沙都子？
Satoko?
まさかゆうべから？
Could it be from last night?
沙都子！
Satoko!
Five thousand thirty-seven.
（沙都子）5,037…
5,038…
Five thousand thirty-eight.
5,039…
Five thousand thirty-nine.
S-Satoko!
さ…沙都子！
Satoko! Satoko!
沙都子！沙都子！
大丈夫か？沙都子
Are you all right, Satoko?
It's me, Keiichi!
俺だ圭一だ
分かるか？聞こえるか？
Understand?
Can you hear me?
K-Keiichi-san...
け…圭一さん…
You're fine now.
もう大丈夫だからな
Because I'll...
Nii-nii will definitely save you.
必ず俺が…
にーにーが助けてやるから
5,040…
Five thousand forty...
5,040って…
Five thousand forty?
お前
いくつまで数えるつもりなんだよ？
What number are you
planning to count to?
Ten thousand...
１万…
Idiot, there's no way you
could count to ten thousand!
バカ野郎！１万なんて
数えられるわけねえだろう
Why are you doing this?
どうしてこんなことを？
叔父さまが…
Uncle...
Where...
Where the hell did he go?
どこへ…どこへ行きやがった？
Irie Medical Clinic
（圭一）もうすぐ着くから
しばらくの間我慢してろ
We're almost there,
so hang in there a bit longer.
な…何だ？
W-What?
何ですの？
パトカーがいっぱいですわよ
What is it?
There are a lot of police cars.
分からない　様子を見てくるから
しばらくここにいろ
I don't know. I'll go check it out,
so stay here for a while.
レディーをバスタオル１枚で
こんなとこに置いてくなんて
You're leaving a lady behind
with just a bath towel here?
なってませんわね…
What a gentleman.
それだけ悪態がつけりゃ大丈夫だ
If you can be
that sarcastic, you'll be fine.
（医師）高熱と失禁に
重度の意識障害も見られました
High fever, incontinence, and
severe mania were observed.
睡眠薬中毒の
典型的な重症例だと思いましたので
I thought it was a typical
case of sleeping-pill overdose...
...so I treated him right away.
直ちに対応に入りました
（小宮山(こみやま)）警察も呼ばずに？
Without calling the police?
ここは病院で私は医師ですよ
This is a hospital,
and I'm a doctor.
命が危険な状態にあるなら
直ちに治療して当然です
If a life is in danger,
of course I'll begin treatment.
（小宮山）まあ…それで？
I guess... And then?
Breathing was abnormal, so
I performed artificial respiration...
呼吸は不正常だったので
人工呼吸を施しました
...combined with
a respiratory stimulant.
併せて呼吸刺激剤を投与
So you did all you could,
but it didn't work out?
つまりいろいろ頑張ったけど
結局ダメだったと
You called after he died?
通報は死んでから直ちに？
（医師）はい
Yes.
（警官）こちら本部こちら本部
This is HQ. This is HQ.
はいもしもし
こちら小宮山です　お疲れさまです
Yes, hello,
this is Komiyama. Good work.
Looks like a sleeping-pill
suicide. No suicide note.
睡眠薬で自殺みたいですね
遺書のたぐいはなし
自殺？一体誰が？
Suicide? Who could it be?
（小宮山）ふだんから
睡眠薬を愛用していたとかは？
Was he using
sleeping pills regularly?
（医師）ないと思いますが
I don't think so.
Did he regularly say things like,
"I'm tired," or "I want to die"?
日ごろ疲れたとか死にたいとか
そんなこと言ってました？
入江(いりえ)先生はふだんから
ああいう性格でしたから
Dr. Irie's personality was always
distinct, so I don't think so...
とても そんなふうには…
入江？監督が自殺？
Irie? The coach
committed suicide?
なんで…
（無線の受信音）
Why?
The chief says
let backup take it...
（警官）
課長からそちらは応援に任せて
行方不明になった大石(おおいし)さんの
捜索に戻れとのことです
...and return to the search
for the missing Oishi-san.
（小宮山）了解しました
Got it.
大石の捜索って何だ？
The search for Oishi? What?
What's going on?
（沙都子）一体何事なんですの？
（圭一）アアッ…
さ…沙都子か
S-Satoko? Don't scare me.
脅かすなよ
（沙都子）何事なんですの？
What's going on?
From what I just heard
the police talking about...
今警察が話してるのを
聞いてたかぎりじゃ監督が―
...it seems the coach
committed suicide.
自殺したらしい…
圭一さんそれ本当ですの？
Keiichi-san, is that true?
何かの
聞き間違いじゃないんですの？
Could you have misheard?
確かにそう聞いたよ
I heard it right.
入江先生が睡眠薬で自殺したって…
They said Irie-sensei committed
suicide with sleeping pills.
ウソ…ウソですわ…
It's a lie.
A lie.
That coach would
never commit suicide...
あの監督が自殺なんて
そんなの絶対に…
すまない
I'm sorry.
Why are you apologizing?
どうして謝りますの？
俺…昨日監督をその…
Yesterday, I said, um...
“お前なんか死んじまえ”って
呪ったんだ
..."You should die,"
and cursed the coach.
I cursed him, so he really died.
呪ったからホントに死んじゃって…
It's not your fault.
圭一さんのせいではありませんわ
It's no one's fault...
誰のせいでも
I don't want to be naked so long.
I want some clothes.
いつまでも裸でいたくありませんわ
服が欲しい
診療所に行って診てもらったほうが
You should get
checked at the clinic...
It's not like I'll die if I'm seen
after wearing some clothes.
服を着てから診てもらっても
別に死にはしませんわ
（圭一）で…でも
B-But...
Let's go to Rika's house.
梨花(りか)の家に行きますわよ
私の服あるはずですから
She should have
some of my clothes.
分かった
All right.
おかしいんだ
（沙都子）何がですの？
It's strange.
What is?
（圭一）
鷹野(たかの)さんが死んだの知ってるか？
Did you know that
Takano-san died?
昨日の話だと
どっかで焼け死んだらしい
I heard yesterday that it seems
she burned to death somewhere.
And it seems that Oishi guy
from the police went missing.
それから警察の大石ってヤツも
行方不明になってるらしい
鷹野さんも監督も大石も―
Takano-san,
the coach, and Oishi...
俺が“死ね”と念じたら
本当に死んでしまったんだ
When I wished for them
to die, they really died.
“念じたら”？
Wished?
（圭一）分からない…
I don't get it.
分からないけど
俺が念じると本当に死んじまうんだ
I don't get it, but when
I wish for it, people really die!
That's not all.
There's something even stranger.
それだけじゃない
もっとおかしいこともあるんだ
It's about your uncle.
それは…お前の叔父なんだ
叔父さまの話は
やめてくださいまし
Please stop talking about him.
昨日いたんだろう？お前の家に
He was at your
house yesterday, right?
Could you please stop talking
about him? I can't stand it!
あの人の話は
やめてくださいます？
イヤなんですの…
There's no way he could be
there after Cotton Drifting night.
あの男が 綿流しの夜以降
いるわけがないんだ
だって…だって…
Because... Because...
イヤ…イヤ！
No... No!
I killed him with these hands!
With these hands!
俺がこの手で殺したんだ
この手で！
On the night of the Cotton
Drifting Festival, I killed your uncle.
俺が綿流しの祭りの夜に
お前の叔父を殺したんだ
So there's no way he could've
come back to your house.
だからお前の家に
帰ってくるなんてことはありえない
Let me down.
下ろして…
（圭一）えっ？
下ろしてくださいまし
Please let me down.
お前も俺のこと―
I bet you also think
I went crazy, huh?
変になっちまったと
思ってるんだろうな…
Since the people you cursed
died by coincidence...
圭一さんはきっと偶然
呪った人が死んでしまったんで
...I bet you're just confused.
混乱してるだけに違いありませんわ
I think you should
rest at home for today.
今日はもうお家(うち)で休んだほうが
よろしいと思います
I'm fine now, so...
私は もう平気ですから
でも俺は沙都子を…
But I... Satoko...
私は
もう本当に大丈夫なんですのよ
I'm really okay now.
男の人にいつまでも
裸をさらしていたくありませんの
I don't want to expose my
naked self to a man any longer.
沙都子…
Satoko...
ウウッ…
ウ…ウソだ…俺は望んでない
N-No way. I didn't wish for this.
There's no way I'd wish
for this, even by mistake!
そんなこと間違っても望むもんか
For this...
そんなこと…そんなこと…
For this!
When They Cry
Sa...
C-Calm down, Satoko!
お…落ち着け沙都子これは違う
It wasn't me!
M-Murder... Murderer...
ひ…ひと…人殺し
沙都子
Satoko!
- Sato...
- No!
さと…
（沙都子）イヤー！
Satoko!
沙都子！
人殺し…人殺し…
Murderer... Murderer...
違う！俺じゃない！
No! It wasn't me!
I didn't kill her!
俺は殺してなんかない！
本当だ！
Really!
一度は本当のにーにーかも
しれないとまで思ったのに
For once, I even thought
you could be my real nii-nii...
Ever since Nii-nii went missing,
I've always been so lonely.
にーにーがいなくなって
ずっと寂しかったけど
But since you transferred here,
everyone became happy...
圭一さんが転校してきてくれて―
またみんな明るくなって
楽しくなって
...things became fun, and
every day was a shiny day, but...
毎日が光ってたのに…
No! You're mistaken, Satoko!
違う！ 違うんだ 沙都子！
（沙都子）どうして…どうして…
Why? Why?
Satoko!
沙都子！
- Satoko!
- S-Stay away, murderer!
沙都子
（沙都子）近寄らないで人殺し！
沙都子俺にも分からないんだ
Satoko, even I don't understand.
でもこれだけは言える
梨花ちゃんを殺したのは俺じゃない
But I can say this.
I didn't kill Rika-chan.
That alone is certain.
それだけは絶対に…
How can I believe that?
どう信じれば
いいっていうんですの？
Satoko... please believe me.
沙都子信じてくれ
俺は…俺は…
I... I...
Then what about that ax?
Why do you have such a thing?
ではそのオノは何なんですの？
なんでそんな物を…
Y-You're scared of this?
これが怖いのか？じゃ捨てるよ
Then I'll throw it away. Here.
ほら
You think I'm relieved because
you threw away your weapon?
武器を捨てたぐらいで
気を許すと思いまして？
圭一さんの力なら私を
素手で絞め殺すなんて簡単でしょう
With your strength, it'd be easy
to just strangle me, right?
じゃどうしたらいい？
Then what should I do?
両手を頭の上で組んで
後ろを向いてくださいませ
Please fold your hands above
your head and turn around.
Is this okay?
これでいいか？
圭一さんが悪くないのは
なんとなく分かってましたわ
I somehow knew
that you weren't bad.
I think you're probably just
possessed by something bad.
多分あなたは何か悪いものに
乗り移られただけなんですの
I know...
分かってるんですの私
身に覚えが
ないわけじゃないんですのよ
It's not like I haven't
experienced it myself.
以前祭具殿の屋根に
よじ登ったことがありますの
I climbed onto the roof
of the ritual tool shrine once.
（梨花）３４５…
Three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, ten.
（子供たちの笑い声）
（梨花）６ ７ ８…
Are you ready?
もういいかい？…です
Ready!
（子供）もういいよ
（沙都子）ウワッ！いたたた…
Ow...
これがオヤシロさま？
This is Oyashiro-sama?
（沙都子）わあ…
Hey, where's Satoko-chan?
（子供）あれ？沙都子ちゃんは？
（梨花）どこにいますですか？
Where did you go?
困りましたわ…
This is bad.
ウワッ！
Mi?
It wasn't me! It wasn't me!
（梨花）ボクじゃないのです
ボクじゃないのです…
ボクじゃないのです
（泣き声）
ボクじゃないのです…
It wasn't me!
（たたく音）
ごめんなさいごめんなさい！
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
（たたく音）
ごめんなさい！
Ever since then, the world
around me became strange.
（沙都子）それからですわ
私の周りの世界が
おかしくなったのは
The world became strange?
世界が おかしく？
分かってるんですの私には
I know that this is
Oyashiro-sama's curse...
これはオヤシロさまのたたりだって
あのとき祭具殿を汚(けが)して
親友を見捨てた―
That this is divine punishment
for defiling the shrine...
...and abandoning my best friend.
私への天罰だって
My parents vanished
in a muddy stream.
父も母も濁流に消えた
意地悪だった叔母も死んだ
My mean aunt also died.
Nii-nii, who cared for
me more than anyone...
誰よりも私を
かわいがってくれたにーにーも
私を捨てて家出してしまった
...abandoned me and
ran away from home.
And... And...
そして…そして…
さ…沙都子
S-Satoko!
When you transferred, I thought
happy days had finally returned...
圭一さんが転校してきて―
やっと 楽しい毎日が
戻ってきたと思っていたのに
今度は圭一さんが取りつかれて
梨花も殺されて…
...but now you've become
possessed, and Rika's been killed.
I can't take this anymore!
もうイヤ…
（泣き声）
Calm down, Satoko!
It's not a curse!
落ち着け沙都子たたりなんかない
No one's bullying you!
誰も
お前をいじめたりなんかしない
No!
イヤー！
ウソだろう…
No way.
ウワーッ！
ウウッ…
（沙都子）死んじゃえ人殺し！
Die, murderer!
Give him back!
Give back Nii-nii!
返してよ　にーにーを返してよ
圭一さんを返してよ！
Give me back Keiichi-san!
さ…沙都子！沙都子！
S-Satoko! Satoko!
私はお前なんかには…
たたりなんかに絶対負けない
I will never lose to you...
never lose to the curse.
I'll never lose to you,
who stole everyone from me!
みんなを奪ったお前になんか
負けたりしなーい！
沙都子…これだけは信じてくれ
Satoko, please just believe this.
I wanted you to be happy...
俺は
お前に幸せになってほしくって…
こいつ
最後の最後で圭一さんのフリを…
Why you...
Pretending to be Keiichi-san
till the very, very end...
Fall!
落ちろ！
落ちてしまえー！
Please believe me...
信じてくれ…
Fall!
落ちろー！
沙都子！
Satoko!
Her last word to me was "fall."
最後の言葉が“落ちろ”だなんて
あまりにも報われない悲しい結末
What a hopeless, sad ending.
Those once-shining
days in Hinamizawa...
輝いていたあの雛見沢(ひなみざわ)での日々は
一体どこへ行ってしまったのか
Where in the world did they go?
No, where did it
start to go wrong?
いやどこから
おかしくなってしまったのか
As I fell,
the last thing I wished for...
落ちながら俺が最期に願ったこと
...was probably the death
of this world of Hinamizawa...
それはこのおかしくなった―
雛見沢という世界そのものの
死かもしれない
...which had gone wrong.
That was staff reporter Ogata
reporting from the PM's home.
（ｷｬｽﾀｰ）首相官邸より報道部の
オガタ記者がお伝えしました
Now, here is another
report on the disaster.
さてここでもう一度
現場の状況をお伝えいたします
（労働者）怖いよな　寝てたら
そのままあの世行きだもんな
Scary, huh? It's like
dying while you're sleeping.
So sad.
（店員）かわいそうにねえ
Oh, some gyoza and a beer.
あっあと餃子(ぎょうざ)とビールちょうだい
（店員）はいよ
Sure. Another gyoza!
６月21日から22日の深夜にかけて
A severe disaster occurred
in Hinamizawa, Shiboneshi.
鹿骨(ししぼね)市雛見沢村にて
大規模な災害が発生しました
詳細はまだ究明されていませんが
Details are still unclear...
...but poisonous volcanic gas
erupted in the district.
雛見沢村地区の某所から
猛毒の火山性ガスが噴出
The gas flow
directly hit the village...
ガス流となり雛見沢村地区を直撃
全世帯が全滅したもようです
...and it seems all
homes were destroyed.
The current confirmed
death toll is over a thousand.
現在確認されている犠牲者は
1,000人以上
The JSDF is
verifying the damage...
自衛隊が被害状況を確認中ですが
その結果更に犠牲者の数は
増えるものと予想されます
...but the death toll is predicted
to increase as a result.
え～なお
ただいま入った情報によりますと
According to newly
received information...
...they've confirmed one survivor.
１名の生存者を確認したもようです
生存者の名前は
雛見沢村在住の前原(まえばら)圭一さん
The survivor's name is Keiichi
Maebara, a Hinamizawa resident.
Keiichi Maebara,
a Hinamizawa resident.
雛見沢村在住の前原圭一さんです
前原さんは救出時ガスによる
呼吸困難で重体に陥っていましたが
He was in critical condition and
respiratory distress from the gas...
...but is now in
a local general hospital.
現在は県内の総合病院に収容
一命を取り留めたもようです
It appears he's been saved.
As more develops...
詳しい状況が分かり…
Who turned it off?
（労働者）
あれ？誰だい？消したの
Oh dear, did the TV break?
（店員）あらヤダ
壊れちゃったのかしらこのテレビ
To get my happiness,
I had done everything...
...but had done nothing
to be blamed and accused of.
The sound of footsteps
became louder every day.
Then I noticed the fact
there was no time.
I was a believer in life,
to be myself always.
And was asking
whether I would be alive.
Give me a reason
why not to adopt in this way.
Or judge me to be guilty
of so many incurable sins.
Tell me why or why not?
Complaining way too much.
Maybe I overlooked
something fatal for me.
Preview
What arrived
is the evening twilight.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）訪れたのは夕暮れの日陰
What got lost
is the darkness of time.
迷い込んだのは時の暗闇
What meets is the space
between past and future.
出会うのは過去と未来の隙間
｢ひぐらしのなく頃に｣
When They Cry.
"Time Wasting" Chapter,
Episode 1: HINAMIZAWA.
- "Time Wasting" Chapter -
Episode 01: HINAMIZAWA
"Time Wasting" Chapter,
Episode 1: HINAMIZAWA.
- "Time Wasting" Chapter -
Episode 01: HINAMIZAWA
Can you believe it?
あなたは信じられますか？